ergotron.com 2019-07-24

# Privacy Policy | Ergotron

#### Ergotron Global Internet Privacy Policy

Ergotron, Inc. (“Ergotron”) recognizes and respects the privacy of our online visitors. It is Ergotron’s policy to comply with all applicable privacy and data protection laws. This commitment reflects the value we place on earning and keeping the trust of our customers, business partners, employees and others who share their Personal Information with us.

This Global Internet Privacy Policy (this “Policy”) applies to your Personal Information and describes how Ergotron, acting as the data controller, protects your privacy when we collect and use Personal Information on Ergotron sites. As used in this Policy, the term “Personal Information” means information that identifies you personally as a natural person, directly or indirectly, in particular in combination with other information available to us such as an identification number, location data, online identifier or one or more factors specific to your identity as a natural person. Ergotron adheres to the highest ethical standards in gathering, using, and safeguarding customer’s Personal Information. This Policy applies, in general, to all internet sites owned by or on behalf of Ergotron, its business units as well as by our service providers, where any of those parties are either located within or outside the European Union.

By using an Ergotron internet site or providing Personal Information to us, you understand the principles for our collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information as described in this Policy. If you do not agree with the terms therein, you must not provide your Personal Information, and we may not be able to communicate with you or provide certain products or services to you.

#### Information We Collect

Information we may request includes your email address, name, home address, and telephone number(s). If you make a purchase, we may ask for your credit card number and other data to process your credit or financing request. For additional information regarding internet domain sites owned by Ergotron, Inc., please contact the legal department at the address listed below.

#### When we collect information

Examples of when we may ask you to provide Personal Information include, but are not limited to, when you:

  * Use any internet domain sites owned by Ergotron;
  * Request quotes, services, support, or information;
  * Place orders for products or services;
  * Participate in surveys, sweepstakes, contests or other promotional activities;
  * Subscribe to promotional emails, newsletters, or other materials;
  * Apply for a job, submit your resume/CV, or create a candidate profile; or,
  * Contact us.

Personal Information may be collected by Ergotron and/or by our third-party service providers acting on our behalf and under our instructions in operating our internet sites and/or providing you with our products or services.

#### Why we collect information

We collect your Personal Information in order to conduct our business functions and operate our services, which include the following:

  * communicating with you and provide you with information about products or services,
  * providing you with our products and services as well as support in relation thereto,
  * conducting surveys, sweepstakes, contests or other promotional activities;
  * promoting and marketing our products and services in particular, but not limited to, _via_ promotional emails, newsletters or other materials,
  * personalizing your experience on our sites or customize any of our products or services,
  * completing necessary financial transactions;
  * performing recall actions;
  * performing statistical analyses;
  * complying with a legal requirement or court order;
  * defending in, initiating or resolving disputes or legal proceedings and performing or enforcing the agreements to which Ergotron, or one of our business units, is a party.

We may otherwise collect, use or disclose your Personal Information, where the collection, use or disclosure is in accordance with this Privacy Policy or any agreement you enter into with us; or required or authorized by applicable law, including without limitation applicable privacy and data protection laws, including (EU) Regulation 2016/679 of 27 April 2016 (the “General Data Protection Regulation” or “GDPR”).

#### Limitations on the Collection, Use and Disclosure of Personal Information

To the extent required by applicable law, whenever Ergotron collects Personal Information on an Ergotron internet site, Ergotron will:

  * Collect, use, disclose and transfer your Personal Information only with your consent when required, depending on the sensitivity of the Personal Information, legal requirements, direct marketing by third parties and other factors;
  * Collect your Personal Information only for specific, limited and legitimate purposes. This information we collect will be relevant, adequate and not excessive for the purposes for which it is collected;
  * Process your Personal Information in a manner consistent with the purpose for which it was originally collected or to which you have subsequently consented;
  * Take commercially reasonable steps to ensure that your Personal Information is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete, and, where necessary, and subject to your updates, kept up-to-date;
  * Not use your Personal Information for direct marketing purposes by Ergotron without giving you an opportunity to “opt-out”; and,
  * Take appropriate measures, by contract or otherwise, to provide adequate technical and organizational protection for Personal Information that we collect and use, and for Personal Information that is disclosed to a third party or transferred to another country, including transfers within Ergotron.

#### Sharing Personal Information

Ergotron will not sell Personal Information collected from its internet sites to mailing list brokers without your express consent.

Ergotron may share your Personal Information with other Ergotron business units. When doing so, these other Ergotron business units will use your Personal Information in a manner consistent with the purposes for which it was originally collected (or to which you subsequently consented) and only as permitted under this Policy, any applicable Country or Web Site Privacy Statements, and all applicable privacy and data protection laws.

Ergotron may also share your Personal Information with third parties we hire to perform support services for us. These third parties are required to use the Personal Information we share with them only to perform services on our behalf and under our instructions, in particular to treat your Personal Information as strictly confidential. In some cases, Ergotron may share your Personal Information with third parties who partner with us to provide products and services to our customers. If we do so, we will require our business partners to use the Personal Information we share with them in a manner consistent with the purpose for which it was originally collected (or to which you subsequently consented) and only as permitted under this Policy, any applicable County or Web Site Privacy Statements, and all applicable privacy and data protection laws.

In certain, limited circumstances, where permitted by applicable law, we may share or transfer Personal Information to unrelated third parties. For example, we may provide Personal Information to a third party (i) at your request; (ii) to comply with a legal requirement or court order; (iii) to investigate a possible crime, such as identity theft; (iv) in connection with the sale, purchase, merger, reorganization, liquidation or dissolution of Ergotron or an Ergotron business unit; or (v) under similar circumstances. If such an event occurs, we will take appropriate steps to protect your Personal Information.

#### Overseas transfers and disclosures

Some of your Personal Information may be transferred, stored, processed or used outside of the U.S.A. and/or outside of the European Union by Ergotron or by third party service providers. This may happen if other Ergotron entities or venture partners are overseas, if we outsource certain activities overseas or if transactions, information, services or products have an overseas connection.

Your Personal Information may also be disclosed to third-party service providers which may store your Personal Information in the U.S.A. and European Union, and such other countries in which those parties or their, or our, computer systems may be located from time to time, where it may be used for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

Where required by applicable privacy and data protection laws, we take steps in order to ensure any overseas transfer of Personal Information is effected in compliance with the appropriate organizational and technical means (including e.g. EU Commission’s model clauses for data transfers or European Commission’s adequacy decisions). Where such parties are located overseas, you may have rights to enforce such parties’ compliance with applicable privacy and data protection laws.

#### Cookies & Information collected via our sites

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. Ergotron and our third-party advertising and analytics providers use cookies and similar technologies on the web site to enable us to provide our products and services and help collect data about use of the sites, including traffic analysis, to record information about your activities on the web site and to ‘remember’ you when you return to the Ergotron web site. Subject to their retention period as stated below, some cookies may remain on your computer until you delete them; others, like session ID cookies, may expire when you close your browser.

You can control cookies by configuring your browser to accept, restrict or reject all or certain cookies, or notify you when a cookie is sent to your browser. Each browser is different, so check the “Help” menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. Cookies are browser specific; thus, if you use multiple devices or web browsers to access Ergotron internet sites, you will need to manage your cookies preferences across these various devices and browsers. If you are using a mobile device to access Ergotron sites, please refer to your instruction manual or other help/settings resource to find out how you can control cookies on your device. You may access Ergotron internet sites even if you rejected all or certain cookies as described above; however, your ability to use some functionality and areas of the Ergotron web site will be limited or the sites may not operate as intended and we might not be able to provide you with certain products or services. See the section “Online Tracking and Your Choices” below for more information on how the Ergotron web site may respond to your browser settings. We do not control the use of cookies by third parties. See the section on “Third-party Advertisers and Analytics Providers” below and review the privacy policies of each of the third party advertising and analytics providers for more information on third party cookie.

For additional detail about how Ergotron processes information collected via our website, please see the Cookie Notice.

#### Third-Party Advertisers and Analytics Providers

Ads appearing on the Ergotron web site may be delivered to users by third-party advertising providers, such as Google. We work with third party advertising providers for purposes such as targeting our advertisements on the Ergotron web site, and, in doing so we may share with those advertising providers, information about users’ use of the Ergotron web site. We use third party advertising and analytics providers, such as Google Analytics, to collect information about Ergotron web site usage and users of our site, including demographic and interest-level information. Our advertising and analytics providers use cookies and Clear GIFs to collect demographic and interest-level information and usage information from users that visit the Ergotron web site, including but not limited to information about the pages where users enter and exit the Ergotron web site, what pages and advertisements users view and visit on the Ergotron web site, and what items users purchase. Cookies and Clear GIFs allow advertisers and analytics providers to recognize a user when a user visits the Ergotron web site, but also when a user visits other websites. Our advertising and analytics providers use the information they collect from the Ergotron web site and other web sites to profile users to display relevant advertising and to share with us and other web site operators’ information about users. We do not link information we receive from our analytics partners with personally identifiable information. For more information regarding Google’s use of cookies and collection and use of information see the Google Privacy Policy. If you would like to opt out of Google Analytics tracking, please go to Google Analytics and change your preferences accordingly.

#### Online Tracking and Your Choices

As discussed above, we track web site usage information through using cookies, Clear GIFs, and other tracking mechanisms. You can manage the settings on your browser or mobile device to delete and disable cookies and other tracking/recording tools. Doing so may impact your experience using the Ergotron web site and may make certain features and areas unavailable to you.  Many advertising companies are also members of the NAI or DAA and provide opt-outs on those industry pages at networkadvertising.org/choices and aboutads.info/choices.

#### Links to Third Party Internet Sites

Ergotron internet sites may contain links to internet sites that are not owned by Ergotron. These links are provided as a convenience and do not imply any endorsement of the activities or content of these sites, nor any association with their operators. Ergotron does not control these internet sites and is not responsible for the content, security, or privacy practices of these internet sites and their owners. We urge you to review the privacy policy posted on these web sites you visit before using the site or providing Personal Information.

#### Retention of Personal Information

Ergotron may retain the Personal Information collected on Ergotron internet sites as long as necessary to provide the services, products and information you request or as mandated or permitted by applicable law (e.g. statute of limitations). If your Personal Information is no longer necessary for purposes for which it is processed and we have no legal obligation to retain that Personal Information, we will remove it from our systems and destroy all record of it. If you would like to update your Personal Information or discontinue our use of your Personal Information, please contact us at the address listed below.

#### Children and Parents

Ergotron does not knowingly solicit or collect Personal Information from or about children on its internet sites except as permitted under applicable law. If you are under 18 years of age, please do not submit any Personal Information through our web sites without the express consent and participation of a parent or guardian. If your child has submitted Personal Information and you would like to request that such Personal Information be deleted from our records, you may do so by contacting us at the address listed below.

#### Your rights

You are entitled to access Personal Information that we hold about you. If you request access to your Personal Information, in ordinary circumstances we will give you access to your Personal Information. However, there may be some legal or administrative reasons to deny access. If we refuse your request to access your Personal Information, we will provide you with reasons for the refusal where we are required by law to give those reasons.

You can access and correct some of your Personal Information through our internet sites by contacting us via telephone or email using the details provided below.

We take all reasonable steps to ensure that any Personal Information we collect and use is accurate, complete and up-to-date. To assist us in this, you need to provide true, accurate, current and complete Personal Information about yourself as requested, and properly update the Personal Information provided to us to keep it true, accurate, current and complete. Please tell us, by contacting us in any of the ways specified in this Privacy Policy, if any change occurs in the Personal Information you provided us or, if you believe that your Personal Information is inaccurate or incomplete, and we will correct the information.

If you reside within the European Union, you have the right to ask for a copy of your Personal Information and/or ask for it to be ported to another provider of your choice where the lawful basis for the processing is (i) (a) a contract or (b) your consent and (ii) by automated means. Please note that such a request could be limited solely to the Personal Information you provided to us or that we hold at that given time, and subject to any relevant legal requirements and exemptions, including identity verification procedures.

#### Changes to this Policy or our Privacy Statements

Ergotron reserves the right to update or modify this Policy at any time and without prior notice by posting the revised version of this Policy on our Ergotron internet sites. Where such changes are substantial, we notify you of the expected changes prior to their entry into force.

#### Contacting Us

If you would like to contact us for any reason regarding our privacy practices and/or would like to discontinue our use of your Personal Information, please write to us at the following address:

If you are not satisfied with our answer or the way we process your Personal Information pursuant to this Privacy Policy, you may also have the right to lodge a complaint with a data protection authority or the competent court. If you reside within the European Union, a list of national data protection authorities can be found [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm).

This notice was last revised 23 May 2018.
